Guide to the Phi Alpha Delta Law Fraternity Phi Alpha Delta Law Fraternity RecordsPapers, 1946-1976
Duke University. University Archives
Phi Alpha Delta Law Fraternity records 1946-1976
Duke University. University Archives
Phi Alpha Delta Law Fraternity (Duke University).
4.7 linear feet linear feet Extent: 2250 Items
Phi Alpha Delta Law Fraternity, International is a professional law fraternity advancing integrity, compassion and courage through service to the student, the school, the profession and the community. This collection includes minutes, correspondence, directories, workshop materials, constitution and by-laws, questionnaires and other material.
RL.01762
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Portions of these materials are restricted by donor request.
Provenance
The Phi Alpha Delta Law Fraternity Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in April 1980.
Historical Note
Phi Alpha Delta began as a "law student league" formed to fight an 1897 ruling made by the Supreme Court of Illinois, which affected law students' admission to the bar association. Following the resolution of this controversy, the league wanted to create a formal association and founded the Lambda Epsilon Fraternity in 1898. In 1902, the fraternity was reorganized and renamed Phi Alpha Delta in order to extend the benefits of the organization to a wider range of the legal profession. More information about the fraternity is available on their website here: http://www.padcommunity.org/about-phi-alpha-delta
Collection Overview
This collection includes minutes, correspondence, directories, workshop materials, constitution and by-laws, questionnaires and other material. Topics covered include Phi Alpha Delta Law Fraternity, International, and its history as well as the Duke University School of Law chapter of the fraternity.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. School of Law; Phi Alpha Delta Law Fraternity, International
Detailed Description of Collection
- Container List, 1946-1976, 4.7 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
  - Phi Alpha Delta Law Fraternity Alumnus Record Card (Box 1)
  - Associate Members Questionnaires, 1974-1975
  - Associate Members Questionnaires (in blue notebook)
  - International Convention Chapter Workshops, 1970 (Box 2)
  - International Convention Chapter Workshops, 1972
  - International Convention Chapter Workshops, 1974 (2 folders)
  - 40th Biennial International Convention Pre-Convention Handbook, 1974
  - 40th Biennial Convention, 1974 August 6-9
  - Pre-Convention Material, 1976
  - Miscellaneous Information
  - Constitution and By-Laws
  - Student Handbook
  - Chapter Officers Manuals
  - Chapter Roll
  - Phi Alpha Delta Law Fraternity: A History
  - Directory, 17th Edition
  - Directory, 18th Edition
  - Check stubs, 1969-1975
  - Correspondence 1946-1952 (binder) (Box 3)
  - By-Laws (binder)
  - Minutes and Correspondence, 1961-1975 (binder)
  - P.A.D. Inns of Court Program, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Law Student Advocate Program
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1975
  - Bank statements, cancelled checks, miscellaneous receipts, 1973-1975
  - Scholarship and Fellowship applications, 1975 and 1976
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1974
  - Placement and Job Materials, 1973-1975